<!--
  #%L
  adept-api
  %%
  Copyright (C) 2012 - 2017 Raytheon BBN Technologies
  %%
  Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  You may obtain a copy of the License at
  
       http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
  
  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  limitations under the License.
  #L%
  -->
<doc id="000e2b447698f12aeb2bf639e8ae38bd">
<headline> </headline>
<post author="kickycan" datetime="2005-08-06T15:50:00" id="p1">
I know there are some people on A2K who are from this region of the country, and I wondered if you guys could tell me what it is about where you live that drew you to it, and what it is that you like, dislike, etc., about where you live.

Albuquerque intrigues me for some reason. I have never been there, but I have always had the impression, for no real reason, mind you, that this is a place where people go to escape. A place for loners and people who want to be left alone. A place for weirdness. Am I off-base on this?

And what about Vegas? Phoenix? San Diego? El Paso? What about the rest of the area? How is the economy looking? How are the people? How's the nightlife? I'd love to hear anything you'd like to share. Thanks.
</post>
<post author="Stray Cat" datetime="2005-08-06T16:28:00" id="p2">
Well, I've always lived in the Northeast, and have never travelled out west. But I have a cousin who grew up in Florida, then moved to Park City, Utah. He's very successful and Park City is a pretty ritzy town. He likes it there pretty well.

But he's travelled a lot -- all over the country, even all over the world. And there are two towns in particular out west that he really likes. One of them that you mentioned, is San Diego. I think he just really likes the weather there, very beautiful and temperate all year round. Sounds like it's a very nice city too.

But there's one place that he's always raved about, and that's Sante Fe, New Mexico. From what he's told me, it's a beautiful, very interesting, very cool town. I've heard a few others say the same thing about Sante Fe.

Sorry, I can't be more informative. But, I'm guessing that Albuquerque is probably like a lot of large cities anywhere in the country, probably kind of nondescript. I guess it depends on what you're looking for. Sounds to me like Sante Fe is the type of place that's more unique, has more of a character all it's own.

Anyway, my cousin has said that if he ever moves, he would move to Sante Fe or San Diego. He said he would never move back east. He hates all the traffic, the crowds, the conjestion of the big cities here. For the same reason, he has said he would never move to L.A. either. He's the type that likes to have some space around.
</post>
<post author="Stray Cat" datetime="2005-08-06T17:53:00" id="p3">
(strolling back in with tail in the air....sitting down)

Hi. I'm back...I just realized something.....

<quote>
A place for loners and people who want to be left alone. A place for weirdness
</quote>

umm.....are you alright, Kickycan? That one line sounds a little forlorn.

Of course, I don't know you....but I've never gotten the impression that you are someone that wants to be left alone. You've always sounded like more of a people person.

...are you sure that is what you want? Just askin'...
</post>
<post author="CalamityJane" datetime="2005-08-06T19:22:00" id="p4">
San Diego: probably the most livable city there is.
Average median age: around 35 years,
population 1,3 million San Diegans (without counties)
weather: perfect, all year round, no humidity and rarely
above 80 F in the summertime
economy: predominately white color industry (small bio tech
firms, Qualcomm, facilities of Merck, Pfizer, Eli Lilly, military,
and a huge service industry)

Housing isn't cheap, but the property tax is only 1 % due to
Prop. 13 (Howard Jarvis). Rents are expensive, but not
comparable to Manhattan.

Here are some info <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/San_Diego">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/San_Diego</a>
and don't forget to look at the attractions.
</post>
<post author="ossobuco" datetime="2005-08-06T20:08:00" id="p5">
As someone moving to albuquerque shortly, I will listen with you. I am moving there because I can afford it, I have some friends there, and... it is a real place, with a real history. Well, every place is real, but I mean a place I can get interested in and am already interested in from the bits I know.

Unfortunately this evening some folks from there are off having fun and are unlikely to answer immediately.

I also love Los Angeles. This is not usual, at least among folks up here in north north. But I can't afford it in my old environs, and it is fairly stressful just to drive a few blocks to my old grocery store (I just visited a few weeks ago.) Walk? You kid. The intersection between my old house and my grocery store is an F intersection, as in the worst traffic. A woman with a bag of groceries trudging ten blocks would be quite the unusual sight, and yes, I've done it.
</post>
</doc>