<DOC id="XIN_ENG_20081203.0154" type="story" >
<HEADLINE>
China urges chemical weapons owners to destroy stockpiles by 2012
deadline
</HEADLINE>
<TEXT>
<P>
China urges chemical weapons owners to destroy stockpiles by 2012 deadline
</P>
<P>
THE HAGUE, Dec. 2 (Xinhua) -- Countries which possess chemical weapons should do
their utmost to comply with the 2012 deadline for the destruction of their
chemical weapons, Chinese ambassador Zhang Jun said Tuesday at an annual meeting
of the states parties to the Chemical Weapons Convention (CWC) in The Hague.
</P>
<P>
Zhang, China's ambassador to the Netherlands and permanent representative to the
Organization for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons (OPCW), said that the
speedy and complete destruction of chemical weapons within the time frame
stipulated by the CWC is the fundamental objective of the convention.
</P>
<P>
China calls on the possessor states to honor their obligations in earnest and
ensure the completion of the destruction by the 2012 deadline, he said on the
first day of the 13th session of  the Conference of the States Parties to the
CWC.
</P>
<P>
To achieve this aim, the OPCW should continue to take the verification of the
destruction as a priority and guarantee adequate resources for its verification,
Zhang said.
</P>
<P>
China believes that industry verification is an important means of enhancing
mutual trust and preventing chemical weapons proliferation, Zhang said. However,
the verification mechanism should be strengthened in a gradual and orderly
manner with due regard to the capacities of concerned states parties, he
stressed.
</P>
<P>
Zhang raised the issue of abandoned chemical weapons by Japan in China during
World War II, saying the weapons still pose a grave threat to lives, properties
and the environment in China six decades on. This year they again caused human
casualties in China.
</P>
<P>
"Although some progress has been made in the disposal of the abandoned chemical
weapons by Japan, not a single item of the munitions has been destroyed," he
said.
</P>
<P>
China is gravely concerned about this and urges Japan to act responsibly and
take effective measures to speed up its work, Zhang said.
</P>
<P>
Zhang paid tribute to the CWC, saying the treaty has yielded significant results
in chemical disarmament and non-proliferation since it came into effect 11 years
ago.
</P>
<P>
But he warned that the complicated situation of international security poses new
challenges to chemical disarmament and non- proliferation, and states parties
need to improve their cooperation to advance the cause.
</P>
<P>
China has always supported the CWC and fulfilled all its obligations under the
treaty, Zhang said. He said China will continue to contribute to the cause of
realizing a chemical weapon- free world.
</P>
<P>
Under the CWC, which came into effect in 1997, all states parties which possess
chemical weapons should destroy the weapons by April 29, 2012. Out of the six
countries which have declared chemical weapons stockpiles so far, four have yet
to complete the destruction of their stockpiles, namely the United States,
Russia, India and Libya.
</P>
</TEXT>
</DOC>
